[upbeat bluegrass music]
[欢快的蓝草音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Doy!
多伊！
Bwah.
哇。
I hereby franchise this planet
我特此特许经营这个星球
in the name of the Krusty Krab.
以蟹堡王的名义。
[laughs]
[loud rumbling]
[笑]
[巨响]
Oh!
[whimpering]
哦！
[呜咽]
Ah.
啊。
Didn't you hear that?
你没听到吗？
Wake up!
醒醒吧！
[loud rumbling]
[巨响]
[whimpers]
Gary,
[呜咽]
加里，
I think there's
someone in the house.
我认为有
房子里有人。
[yawns]
[哈欠]
Aah!
啊啊！
[loud crash]
[巨响]
It's coming from downstairs.
是从楼下传来的。
I'm scared,
but we got to go down there.
我很害怕，
但我们必须去那里。
[meows]
[喵喵]
Yes.
是的。
- [meows]
- Yes.
- [喵]
- 是的。
- [meows]
- Yes.
- [喵]
- 是的。
- [meows]
- Yes.
- [喵]
- 是的。
- [meows]
- Yes!
- [喵]
- 是的！
[laughing evilly]
[邪恶地笑]
[shuddering]
[颤抖]
Okay, Gare Bear,
when I flip on the lights,
好吧，盖尔熊，
当我打开灯时
you bark at the burglars.
你对着窃贼狂吠。
[meows]
[喵喵]
I mean roar,
roar at the burglars,
我的意思是咆哮，
对窃贼咆哮，
like the fierce jungle
snail you are.
就像凶猛的丛林
你是蜗牛。
[meows]
[喵喵]
[growling]
[咆哮]
[roaring]
[meows]
- Huh?
[喵喵]
- 啊？
Narlene?
纳琳？
Oh! Well, if it ain't
my old pal Gary.
哦！好吧，如果不是的话
我的老朋友加里。
[meows]
[喵喵]
Oh!
哦！
Narlene Narwhal?
纳琳独角鲸？
I haven't seen
you since we were kids.
我没见过
从我们小时候起就有你。
both: Memory hug.
两者：记忆拥抱。
[SpongeBob whimpering,
Narlene laughing]
[海绵宝宝呜咽，
纳琳笑了]
Oh, look at you, SpongeBob.
哦，看看你，海绵宝宝。
All grown-up-ified and proper.
一切都成熟了、得体了。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
You came to visit moi?
你是来拜访我的吗？
Well, you always said,
嗯，你总是说，
"If you're ever
in Bikini Bottom, Narlene,
“如果你曾经
比基尼泳裤，Narlene，
you can stay with me
as long as you like."
你可以留在我身边
只要你愿意。”
[laughs]
[笑]
Yeah, that sounds
like something I'd say.
是的，听起来
就像我想说的那样。
Too bad your little brother
Nobby isn't here, too.
可惜了你的弟弟
诺比也不在这里。
Oh, he's here. Hey, Nobby!
哦，他来了。嘿，诺比！
Shake a horn and get on in here!
摇一摇喇叭，就到这里来吧！
[speaking gibberish]
[胡言乱语]
Howdy, SpongeBob.
你好，海绵宝宝。
[speaking gibberish]
[胡言乱语]
[coughs]
Wow, Nobby. You sure got big.
[咳嗽]
哇，诺比。你确实长大了。
I need some vittles.
我需要一些食物。
My fridge is
your fridge, Nobert.
我的冰箱是
你的冰箱，诺伯特。
[upbeat bluegrass music]
[欢快的蓝草音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ah, we had a lot of good times
啊，我们度过了很多美好的时光
riding through the woods
in your wagon.
骑马穿过树林
在你的马车里。
[sniffs]
Ah, I can almost
[嗅嗅]
啊，我几乎可以
smell the sea mule.
[sniffs]
闻海骡子的味道。
[嗅嗅]
Huh?
- Hee-haw!
啊？
- 嘻哈！
He remembers you, too.
他也记得你。
[laughter]
[笑声]
[braying]
[叫声]
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
[yawns]
[哈欠]
Oh! Aah!
哦！啊啊！
Sorry, Narlene!
I didn't know you were in here!
对不起，纳琳！
我不知道你在这里！
Morning, SpongeBob.
早上好，海绵宝宝。
I just love your
fancy whirlpool bathtub.
我就是爱你
精美的漩涡浴缸。
[toilet flushes]
Whoo!
[厕所冲水]
呼！
[laughing]
[笑]
Would you be a darling
and hand me a scrub brush?
你会是一个亲爱的吗
递给我一把刷子？
- Oh!
- Thank you.
- 哦！
- 谢谢。
[laughs]
[笑]
Hurry it up.
快点吧。
Other people need
to use the whirlpool bathtub.
其他人需要
使用漩涡浴缸。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ahhh...
啊啊...
[meows]
[喵喵]
[upbeat bluegrass music]
[欢快的蓝草音乐]
Yeah.
是的。
♪ ♪
♪♪
[turkey gobbling]
[火鸡狼吞虎咽]
Ah, Thanksgiving.
啊，感恩节。
[grunting goofily]
[愚蠢地咕哝]
Huh?
啊？
[grunting goofily]
[愚蠢地咕哝]
Aah!
啊啊！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ta-da!
- Oh.
哒哒！
- 哦。
Hoo-hoo! Let's go.
呼呼！我们走吧。
I hope you don't mind
that we made
我希望你不介意
我们做的
your house all hill-ified.
你的房子全是山地化的。
Hill-ified?
希尔化？
Why, I'm...
为什么，我...
thrill-ified.
兴奋化。
Yee-hoo!
呀呼！
[knock on door]
[敲门]
Howdy. Is Narlene here?
你好。纳琳在吗？
It's Cousin WillyBob!
这是威利鲍勃表弟！
Ha ha!
哈哈！
WillyBob, meet SpongeBob.
威利鲍勃，遇见海绵宝宝。
Hey, SpongeBob, meet WillyBob.
嘿，海绵宝宝，来认识一下威利鲍勃吧。
Hoo-hoo-hoo!
呼呼呼！
Well, any cousin of Narlene's
好吧，纳琳的任何表弟
is a cousin of mine, WillyBob.
是我的表弟，威利鲍勃。
Well, much obliged, CousinBob.
嗯，非常感谢，鲍勃表弟。
Come on, Nobby, let's wrassle!
来吧，诺比，我们来打一架吧！
Yeah!
是的！
Hey, cousins, save some for me.
嘿，表弟们，给我留点吧。
[growls]
[咆哮]
[knocking on door]
Huh?
[敲门]
啊？
Is Narlene here?
纳琳在吗？
Welcome, welcome.
欢迎，欢迎。
Any cousin of Narlene's is a...
纳琳的任何表弟都是……
[knocking on door]
Huh.
[敲门]
呵呵。
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
[meows]
[喵喵]
[bluegrass music playing]
[蓝草音乐演奏]
♪ ♪
[growls angrily]
[愤怒地咆哮]
♪ ♪
Hey, Cousin SquidBob,
嘿，鱿鱼鲍勃表弟，
let's square-dance.
我们来跳广场舞吧。
[Squidward yelling]
[章鱼哥大喊]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Breaking news!
突发新闻！
Bikini Bottom
is under siege from narwhals.
比基尼泳裤
受到独角鲸的围攻。
Toothless hoards
of backwoods hill folk
无牙囤积者
边远山区的民俗
are plaguing citizens
with jug-band music,
正在困扰公民
伴随着壶乐队音乐，
hog calling, and bad grammar.
胡言乱语，语法错误。
Citizens are advised
to stay indoors
建议市民
待在室内
and to avoid stomping your feet
to the country-fied beat.
并避免跺脚
配合乡村节奏。
Aah!
啊啊！
They's here! Save yourselves!
他们来了！救救你们自己吧！
Aah!
[static whirs]
啊啊！
[静电呼呼声]
Yikes.
哎呀。
I think maybe it's time
我想也许是时候了
to ask your kin
to leave, Narlene.
去问你的亲戚
离开吧，纳琳。
They're not my kin.
他们不是我的亲戚。
I thought they was your kin.
我以为他们是你的亲戚。
WillyBob is our only relation.
威利鲍勃是我们唯一的亲戚。
[speaking gibberish]
[胡言乱语]
Nobby's right.
诺比是对的。
The rest of them
ain't even narwhals.
其余的人
连独角鲸都不是。
[speaking gibberish]
[胡言乱语]
They're Nearwhals.
他们是近鲸。
Phony little varmint.
虚伪的小害虫。
Kin or no kin,
有亲属或无亲属，
we got to hog-tie this hoedown.
我们必须把这个锄头绑起来。
Well, the good news is...
嗯，好消息是...
I think I know someone
who can help us.
我想我认识一个人
谁可以帮助我们。
[cheers]
[干杯]
[speaking gibberish]
[胡言乱语]
What's the bad news?
坏消息是什么？
Sure.
当然。
I can get rid of those
Nearwhal nimrods for you.
我可以摆脱那些
近鲸尼姆罗德给你。
[laughs evilly]
[邪恶地笑]
Their stupid family
has been feuding
他们愚蠢的一家人
一直在争吵
with my stupid family for years.
和我愚蠢的家人在一起很多年了。
Oh, I seen it.
哦，我看到了。
Them Planktons sure
know how to hold a grudge.
他们肯定是浮游生物
懂得记仇。
Mm-mm-mm-mm-mm.
毫米-毫米-毫米-毫米-毫米。
Ah.
[grunts]
啊。
[咕哝]
[light banjo music]
[轻班卓琴音乐]
[phone ringing]
[电话铃声]
Aah!
啊啊！
How do?
怎么办？
Nearwhals!
近鲸！
all: Nearwhals?
所有人：近鲸？
Nearwhals?
近鲸？
Feud!
世仇！
Voilà! Huh?
瞧！啊？
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
[upbeat bluegrass music]
[欢快的蓝草音乐]
Get them Nearwhals!
抓住他们近鲸！
♪ ♪
♪♪
[speaking gibberish]
[胡言乱语]
Huh?
啊？
Consarn Nearwhals!
康萨恩近鲸！
[rapid chomping]
[快速咀嚼]
Give 'em the itch, Planktons.
让他们感到痒痒吧，浮游生物。
It's a plankton sneak attack.
这是浮游生物的偷袭。
Nearwhals, retreat!
近鲸们，撤退！
[horn blaring]
[喇叭声]
What's that, now?
那是什么，现在？
[horns blaring]
[喇叭声]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Yeah!
[laughter]
是的！
[笑声]
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
Thank you.
谢谢。
Yeah!
是的！
I think someone deserves
a little kiss.
我认为有人值得
一个小小的吻。
Ooh!
[smooching]
哦！
[接吻]
Ew.
呃。
Thankee, Cousin Plankee.
谢谢，普兰基表弟。
[giggles]
- [grunting]
[咯咯笑]
- [咕哝]
Yuck.
恶心。
♪ ♪
♪♪
[speaking gibberish]
[胡言乱语]
Y'all take care now.
[speaking gibberish]
你们现在要保重。
[胡言乱语]
[laughs]
I already miss you guys.
[笑]
我已经想念你们了。
Will you come back
and visit us real soon?
你会回来吗
很快就会来拜访我们吗？
Sooner than you think.
比你想象的要早。
Hyah!
- [speaking gibberish]
哈！
- [胡言乱语]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[crying, sniffles]
[哭泣、抽鼻子]
Hey, Squidward!
嘿，章鱼哥！
What the...
什么...
Hey, Squidward!
嘿，章鱼哥！
Remember back in camp
you used to always say,
记得回到营地
你以前总是说，
"If you're ever
in town, Narlene,
“如果你曾经
在纳琳镇，
you can stay with me anytime!"
你可以随时陪在我身边！”
- I never said that!
- [donkey brays]
-我从来没有这么说过！
- [驴子嘶叫]